<!DOCTYPE webpage
PUBLIC "-//Norman Walsh//DTD Website V2.6.0//EN"
"http://docbook.sourceforge.net/release/website/2.6.0/schema/dtd/website.dtd"[
<!ENTITY download.xml SYSTEM "download.xml" NDATA XML>
<!ENTITY download_stat.xml SYSTEM "download_stat.xml" NDATA XML>
]>


<webpage id="Home">
    <config param="desc" value="PROOF on Demand"/>
    
    
    <head>
        <title>PROOF on Demand</title>
        <summary>Home</summary>
        <keywords>PoD, Anar Manafov, PROOF on Demand</keywords>
    </head>
    
    <webtoc/>
    
    
    <section><title>What is a PoD?</title>
        <para>
            <emphasis role="bold">PROOF on Demand (PoD)</emphasis> is a tool-set
            developed at <ulink url="http://www.gsi.de">GSI</ulink>, which sets up a 
            <ulink url="http://root.cern.ch/drupal/category/package-context/proof">PROOF</ulink> cluster on any resource management system.
            PoD is a user oriented product with an easy to use GUI and a command-line interface. It is fully automated.
            No administrative privileges or special knowledge is required to use it. PoD gives users, who don't have a centrally-administrated
            static PROOF cluster at their institutions, the possibility to enjoy the full power of interactive analysis with PROOF.
        </para>
        <para>
            PoD is a specially designed solution to provide a PROOF cluster on the fly.
        </para>
    </section>
    
    <section><title>Features</title>
        
        <itemizedlist>
            
            <listitem><para><emphasis role="bold">Easy to use</emphasis></para>
                <para>
                    The process of installation is very simple and fully automated.
                    PoD works out of the box. Its distribution contains preconfigured modules and everything users need to
                    just immediately start to work with it right after the installation.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            
            <listitem><para><emphasis role="bold">GUI &amp; Command-line</emphasis></para>
                <para>
                    PoD provides a simple and intuitive graphics user interface in order to simplify access to its functionality.
                    For user’s convenience there is also a command line interface, it helps to manage a PoD cluster remotely or use it in a batch mode.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            
            <listitem><para><emphasis role="bold">Native PROOF connections</emphasis></para>
                <para>
                    Whenever possible, PoD setups direct PROOF connections between nodes. It results in a full functional PROOF cluster.
                    Users get native speed and the whole range of PROOF features. To use native connections an incoming traffic must be allowed
                    on PoD workers for a defined port. Otherwise PoD uses packet-forwarding algorithms.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            
            <listitem><para><emphasis role="bold">Packet-forwarding</emphasis></para>
                <para>
                    When worker nodes are behind a firewall then PoD uses its packet-forwarding algorithms to maintain the PROOF traffic.
                    The algorithms are very efficient, there will be no speed penalty, but some PROOF functions are limited.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            
            <listitem><para><emphasis role="bold">Multiuser/-core environment</emphasis></para>
                <para>
                    PoD implements automatic port mapping algorithms to properly handle cases when several users start PoD instances
                    (servers/ workers) on the same machine. PoD also automatically manages situations when multiple PoD workers are started on the same node.
                    Private PoD instances can’t disturb each other.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            
            <listitem><para><emphasis role="bold">Different job managers</emphasis></para>
                <para>
                    PoD supports different job managers via a plug-in system. It is a very easy to extend system.
                    PoD currently is shipped with the following plug-ins:
                </para>
                <itemizedlist>
                    <listitem><para>SSH,</para></listitem>
                    <listitem><para>LSF (Load Sharing Facility),</para></listitem>
                    <listitem><para>PBS Pro/OpenPBS/Torque (Portable Batch System),</para></listitem>
                    <listitem><para>Grid Engine (Oracle/Sun Grid Engine),</para></listitem>
                    <listitem><para>Condor,</para></listitem>                    
                    <listitem><para>gLite.</para></listitem>
                </itemizedlist>
            </listitem>
            
            
        </itemizedlist>
        
    </section>
    
    <section id="whatsnew">
        <title>What's New</title>
        <variablelist>

            <varlistentry><term>2011-01-13</term>
                <listitem>
                    <para> PoD v3.1.3 was <olink targetdocent="download.xml">released</olink>.
                    It is a patch release for PoD 3.1.
                    See <ulink url="http://proof-on-demand.blogspot.com/2011/01/pod-313.html">the blog post</ulink> for more information.</para>
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>

            <varlistentry><term>2011-01-07</term>
                <listitem>
                    <para> PoD v3.1 was <olink targetdocent="download.xml">released</olink>.</para>
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
            
            <varlistentry><term>2010-12-09</term>
                <listitem>
                    <para> A Condor plug-in for PoD was released in early beta.
                        Please check <ulink url="http://proof-on-demand.blogspot.com/2010/12/condor-plug-in-for-pod.html">the blog post</ulink>.
                        If you want to check this release out, please use the latest <ulink url="http://pod.gsi.de/releases/pod/nightly/">nightly build</ulink>.
                    </para>
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>            
            
            <varlistentry><term>2010-11-14</term>
                <listitem>
                    <para> PoD v2.4 was <olink targetdocent="download.xml">released</olink>.</para>
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
            
            <varlistentry><term>2010-11-04</term>
                <listitem>
                    <para> PoD website has been updated with <olink targetdocent="download_stat.xml">download statistics</olink>.
                        The statistics page is avaliable from the <olink targetdocent="download.xml">download</olink> page</para>
                </listitem>
            </varlistentry>
            
            
        </variablelist>
    </section>
    
</webpage>

<!--
 Local variables:
 mode: docbook
 End:
 -->
