<!DOCTYPE webpage
  PUBLIC "-//Norman Walsh//DTD Website V2.6.0//EN"
  "http://docbook.sourceforge.net/release/website/2.6.0/schema/dtd/website.dtd">

<webpage id="Home">
<config param="desc" value="PROOF on Demand"/>


<head>
<title>PROOF on Demand</title>
<summary>Home</summary>
<keywords>PoD, Anar Manafov, PROOF on Demand</keywords>
</head>

<webtoc/>


<section><title>What is a PoD?</title>
<para>
<emphasis role="bold">PROOF on Demand (PoD)</emphasis> is a set of utilities developed at <ulink url="http://www.gsi.de">GSI</ulink>, which allows starting a
 <ulink url="http://root.cern.ch/drupal/category/package-context/proof">PROOF</ulink> cluster at user request,
 on any resource management system. Installation is simple and doesn’t require administrator privileges, and all the
 processes run in user space. PoD gives users, who don’t have a centrally-administrated static PROOF cluster at their
 institute, the possibility to enjoy the full power of interactive analysis with PROOF.
</para>
<para>
PoD is a specially designed solution to provide a PROOF cluster on the fly.
</para>
</section>

<section><title>Features</title>

<itemizedlist>

<listitem><para><emphasis role="bold">Easy to use</emphasis></para>
<para>
The process of installation is very simple and fully automated.
PoD works out of the box. Its distribution contains precofigured modules and everything users need to
just immediately start to work with it right after the installation.
</para>
</listitem>

<listitem><para><emphasis role="bold">GUI &amp; Command-line</emphasis></para>
<para>
PoD provides a simple and intuitive graphics user interface in order to simplify access to its functionality.
For user’s convenience there is also a command line interface, it helps to manage a PoD cluster remotely or use it in a batch mode.
</para>
</listitem>

<listitem><para><emphasis role="bold">Native PROOF connections</emphasis></para>
<para>
Whenever possible, PoD setups direct PROOF connections between nodes. It results in a full functional PROOF cluster.
Users get native speed and the whole range of PROOF features. To use native connections an incoming traffic must be allowed
on PoD workers for a defined port. Otherwise PoD uses packet-forwarding algorithms.
</para>
</listitem>

<listitem><para><emphasis role="bold">Packet-forwarding</emphasis></para>
<para>
When worker nodes are behind a firewall then PoD uses its packet-forwarding algorithms to maintain the PROOF traffic.
The algorithms are very efficient, there will be no speed penalty, but some PROOF functions are limited.
</para>
</listitem>

<listitem><para><emphasis role="bold">Multiuser/-core environment</emphasis></para>
<para>
PoD implements automatic port mapping algorithms to properly handle cases when several users start PoD instances
(servers/ workers) on the same machine. PoD also automatically manages situations when multiple PoD workers are started on the same node.
Private PoD instances can’t disturb each other.
</para>
</listitem>

<listitem><para><emphasis role="bold">Different job managers</emphasis></para>
<para>
PoD supports different job managers via a plug-in system. It is a very easy to extend system.
PoD currently supports gLite and LSF. PoD v2.1.4 will be shipped with a PBS plug-in.
In future versions more plug-ins will be implemented (SSH, Condor and SGE).
</para>
</listitem>


</itemizedlist>

</section>

<section id="whatsnew">
<title>What's New</title>
<variablelist>

<varlistentry><term>2010-04-08</term>
<listitem>
<para>TORQUE/PBS plug-in beta is out. See a PoD blog <ulink url="http://proof-on-demand.blogspot.com/2010/04/torquepbs-plug-in.html">post</ulink></para>
</listitem>
</varlistentry>


<varlistentry><term>2010-02-03</term>
<listitem>
<para>PoD home site is build now using <ulink url="http://docbook.sourceforge.net/release/website/example/">docbook-website</ulink> technology.</para>
</listitem>
</varlistentry>


</variablelist>
</section>

</webpage>

<!--
Local variables:
mode: docbook
End:
-->
